Here, we have the dog object with a couple properties on it.
لدينا هنا كائن كلب بخاصيتين.
Three of which are actually methods.
ثلاث منها هي أساليب في الواقع.
Let's check out each of these methods and see how each of them can
لنفحص كل أسلوب من هذه الأساليب ونرى كيفية وصول كل أسلوب منها
access the dog object using the special "this" keyword.
إلى كائن الكلب باستخدام الكلمة الأساسية الخاصة "this".
Let's start off the very top, "whatIsThis".
لنبدأ بالأسلوب الموجود بالأعلى، وهو "whatIsThis".
If we called "whatIsThis" on dog,
إذا أطلقنا عليه اسم "whatIsThis" على كائن الكلب،
all it's going to do is print out the value of "this" to the console.
كل ما ستفعله هو طباعة قيمة "this" إلى وحدة التحكم.
So let's see what this looks like.
دعونا نرى الشكل الذي سيبدو عليه.
Pretty interesting. So it looks like we have
إنه أمر شيق. حسنًا، يبدو أننا
an object with a couple of properties on it: name,
لدينا كائن بمجموعة من الخصائص وهي: الاسم،
age, "whatIsThis", woof, and "ageOneYear".
والعمر، و"whatIsThis"، والنباح، و"ageOneYear".
It's actually the same set of properties as the properties in dog
إنها حقًا مجموعة الخصائص نفسها مثل الخصائص في الكلب
because "this" refers to the dog object itself.
لأن "this" يشير إلى كائن الكلب نفسه.
That's pretty straightforward. Check out the next one.
هذا واضح للغاية. تحقق من الخاصية التالية.
If we call the "woof" on dog,
إذا أطلقنا عليها اسم "woof" على كائن الكلب،
what we get printed to the console is the message, "Jodi says 'woof!'"
فما نطبعه إلى وحدة التحكم هي الرسالة، "جودي تصدر نباحًا!"
So, let's kind of explore how it does that.
حسنًا، لنستكشف كيف يفعل ذلك.
So when woof, what's your console logging is
حسنًا عندما يكون النباح الذي تسجله وحدة التحكم
this.name concatenated with a string says "woof".
هو this.name المتسلسل مع سلسلة تصدر "نباحًا".
So, we know for the example that "this",
حسنًا، على سبيل المثال، نحن نعرف أن "this"
just refers to the dog object.
يشير إلى كائن الكلب.
So, this is dog,
حسنًا، هذا كائن الكلب،
accessing the name property gets us the string "Jodi".
إن الوصول إلى خاصية الاسم يوفر لنا سلسلة "جودي".
So if you add that together this.name which is Jodi plus "says 'woof!'",
حسنًا، إذا أضفتم هذا معًا this.name الذي يكون جودي زائد "يصدر نباحًا!"،
you get "Jodi says 'woof!'".
فستحصلون على "جودي يصدر نباحًا!".
Great. So we'll check out the next one, "ageOneYear".
هذا رائع. حسنًا، سنتحقق من الخاصية التالية، "ageOneYear".
Let's go ahead and call this one on dog.
لنتابع ونستدعي ذلك في كائن الكلب.
It looks like what we get is current age: 8.
يبدو أن ما نحصل عليه هو العمر الحالي: 8.
So how does it do that?
كيف يفعل ذلك؟
Let's take a look a little more closely at the "ageOneYear" method.
لنلقِ نظرة عن كثب أكثر على أسلوب "ageOneYear".
So, we see that it accesses the this.age property and increments that by a value of 1.
حسنًا، نرى أنه يصل إلى خاصية this.age والزيادات التي تكون بقيمة 1.
Well, again we know "this" refers to a dog.
حسنًا، مرة أخرى نحن نعرف أن "this" تشير إلى كلب.
So if we grab the age property of dog,
لذا إذا أخذنا الخاصية العمرية للكلب،
we can see that it's a value of 7.
يمكننا أن نرى أنه قيمة 7.
And then 7 incremented by 1,
ثم ازدادت القيمة 7 بمقدار 1،
is going to give you 8.
لتصبح 8.
And after that, all the method does is
وبعد لك، كل ما يفعله الأسلوب
that it's going to print the console the string "Current
هو أنه سيقوم بطباعة وحدة التحكم والسطر "العمر
age" and concatenate that with this.age which is now going to be 8.
الحالي" ويسلسل هذا مع this.age الذي يصبح الآن 8.
So, "ageOneYear" can not only access the age property of the dog object,
حسنًا، لا يمكن لـ "ageOneYear" الوصول إلى الخاصية العمرية لكائن الكلاب فحسب،
it can also directly mutate it by incrementing it by a value of 1.
بل يمكن أيضًا تحويره مباشرةً عن طريق زيادة قيمته بمقدار 1.
So everything you just saw here was possible using
حسنًا كان من الممكن تطبيق كل ما رأيتموه هنا باستخدام
the "this" keyword which gives methods access to the object on which it was called.
الكلمة الرئيسية "this" التي تعطي الأساليب إمكانية الوصول إلى الكائن الذي تم استدعاؤه عليه.